Preliminary Guide to the Barbara Shor Papers, 1953-2000 and undated (bulk [1970's]-1998)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Barbara Shor papers 1953-2000 and undated, bulk 1970s-1998
Shor, Barbara
21 linear feet Extent: 5159 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01179
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
In addition, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Barbara Shor Papers was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001.
Biographical Note
Writer, dream workshop leader, and director of Dreamgates Communities in New York, N.Y. Shor died in 2001.
Collection Overview
Oracles and books on divination (01-045)(28 items, 1.8 linear feet; dated ca. 1970s-1990s and undated), including 17 decks of tarot and other cards, many enclosed in fabric or leather. Shore designed two of the decks, The Earth Alliance Deck and The Earthrise Deck. Also includes sets of runes and I Ching coins, a pendulum, an edition of the I CHING, a rune book edited by Ralph Blum, and other printed material regarding the I CHING and tarot cards.
The addition (01-248) (5131 items, 19.2 linear feet; dated 1953-2000, bulk 1970s-ca. 1998) documents Shor's work on dreams. Includes 41 volumes of meditation and dream journals by Shore (1974-1999); other journals and dream documentation and interpretation by Shor and others; correspondence; and dream-related periodicals, including Dream Network Bulletin. There are also drafts of Shor's poems, short stories, essays, and dream handbooks (ca. 1953-2000), including Unexpected Gifts, Open Channel, Dreaming with Angels, Shared Dreaming, Dream Tool Kit: How to Remember and Encode Your Own Dreams, Small Gifts, and The Swan; records from the Dreamgate Shared Dreaming Project; notes on or from other dream-related workshops; 11 black-and-white and 3 color photographs; and 197 computer disks containing circa 9800 electronic documents.
Subject Headings
Shor, Barbara; Yi jing.; Dream interpretation; Occultism; Divination; Fortune-telling; Fortune-telling by Chinese characters; Runes; Tarot; Tarot cards; Tarot cards -- Private collections; Oracles; Dreams; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Machine-readable records; Floppy disks
Contents of Collection
- Accessions 2001-0045 and 2001-0248
  Users must obtain the donor's permission before quoting from any part of the materials in boxes 4-32. In addition, boxes 4-16 may contain sensitive information, including personal details of the lives and dreams of Shor's family members, clients, friends, and participants in dream projects. This sensitive material restriction is in force for 50 years after the date of the latest document in the accession, and patrons must agree to keep photocopies of these documents for their personal use only. Patrons must sign a waiver concerning these restrictions on publication, on revealing private information, and on conveying photocopies to anyone else. Contact Research Services.
  - Oracles (divination tools) and books on divination
    - Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - 9th Dimension Tarot Cards (Box 1)
      [Includes notes made by Shor, 1972.]
    - Spanish Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - La Fontaine Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - Native American Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - Egyptian Gypsies Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - French Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - The New Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - The Stairs of Gold Tarot Cards (Box 1)
    - The Book of Runes, Ralph Blum edition (Box 1)
      [The book includes notes by Shor. The actual runes can be found in the larger of the two leather pouches in box 2.]
    - 5 packs of Tarot and other cards enclosed in various fabrics or scarves (Box 2)
      [The deck used by Shor when she did readings is inside a blue silk bag with silver dragons on it. The silk came from a friend's trip to Asia. The bead may come from Crete. Andrew Ramer sewed the bag. The Earth Alliance Deck, created by Shor, is wrapped in turquoise silk. A friend produced the computer images. See box 13 for further Earth Alliance material. The Earthrise Deck, also created by Shor, is wrapped in red silk inside a leather pouch. The pouch may be of deer hide and may have been given to her by Joseph Real. She created the Earthrise Deck because of her frustration with the limitations of the tarot and from her own experiences. She often used the Earthrise Deck in conjunction with the tarot cards in her readings. A further description of the cards in this deck compiled by Andrew Ramer can be found in the inventory drawers in Rubenstein Library. A blue pouch contains The Angel Oracle, described in the book Ask Your Angels that was coauthored by Andrew Ramer and edited in part by Shor.]
    - Wooden box
      - Shor's pendulum (Box 2)
      - Two oracles created by Andrew Ramer (Box 2)
        [One, in blue denim, is based on the Semitic alphabet and sometimes called Hebe Runes. The other is a tribal oracle written on 3x5 cards.]
      - Two sets of I Ching coins (Box 2)
      - Shor's first set of runes (Box 2)
        [Composed of 8 handmade tiles in a blue pouch. Also includes Shor's descriptions of the tiles.]
      - A child's oracle (Box 2)
    - Set of runes enclosed in a leather bag (Box 2)
      [Used in conjunction with the The Book of Runes, Ralph Blum edition in box 1.
    - Printed material on the I Ching and the Tarot (Box 3)
    - Packs of Dream Cards; Flower Power (Ancient Herbal Remedy) Cards; I Ching Cards; Destiny cards (Box 3)
  - Writings, workshop and seminar material, correspondence, subject files, and ephemera
    - Printed material regarding dreams and poetry, including Shor's Sea Change, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Drafts of poetry, ca. 1976-ca. 1996 (Box 4)
    - Draft of Unexpected Gifts, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Drafts of essays, 1978-1996 (Box 4-5)
    - Dream Lexicon (Box 5)
    - Draft of Open Channel, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Drafts of poems and stories (Box 5)
    - Draft of Dreaming with Angels, 1994 (Box 5-6)
    - Draft of Shared Dreaming, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Workshops and seminars (Box 6)
    - Poseidia Dreams, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
    - Shared Dreaming (Box 7)
    - Dream Extras, 1987-1992 (Box 8)
    - Dream magazines, 1982-1992 (Box 8)
    - Dream Dialog, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence and dreams, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Dreams, 1987-1999 (Box 8)
    - Workshop notes (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Dreams and dream lexicon, organized by Shor according to topic (Box 9)
    - Notes and other materials on various dream events, including the New York Shared Dreaming Project (Box 9)
    - Dreamgate Shared Dreaming Project, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Dreams and dream lexicon, organized by Shor according to topic (Box 10)
    - Dream Tool Kit: How to Remember and Encode Your Own Dreams, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Dreams and dream lexicon, organized by Shor according to topic (Box 11)
    - Correspondence (Box 11)
    - Shared Dreaming Project, 1988-1989 (Box 11-12)
    - Dream Network Bulletin and other dream publications, 1988-1998 (Box 12)
    - Drafts of poetry (Box 12)
    - Correspondence from clients and daughter (Box 12)
    - Dreams (Box 12)
    - Drafts of articles (Box 12)
    - Drafts of stories and poems, including from Small Gifts and The Swan (Box 13)
    - The Harmonic Convergence Book of Dreams, ed. Charles Upton, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Earth Alliance (Box 13)
    - Notes from conferences attended (Box 14)
    - Material on copyright (Box 14)
    - Rhoda Nathans black and white photographs, including one of Merce Cunningham, and publications by Michael Andron (Box 14)
    - Draft of Open Channel, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Drafts of High School newspaper columns, 1953 (Box 14)
    - Early poetry, The box of unstrung words... (Box 14)
    - Draft of Dream Tool Kit and other articles (Box 14)
    - Notebook on t'ai chi ch'uan, pressure points, and yoga (Box 15)
    - Drafts of poetry, stories, and essays, including God's Cookbook, 1995; The Reluctant Medium; Mucky Boots; The Black-Headed People: A Story of Ancient Summer; Earth Rise; two Grover stories; Among the Trees, 1996 (Box 15-16)
  - Journals
    - 2 [journals,] some of dreams, 1991 and undated (Box 16)
    - Table of Contents, 1987-1994, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Journal NYC, 1974-1976, (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Journals, Sky Notch #1-3 and Transition to New York, #4, 1976, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Journals, #6-7, New York, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Journal, Aspen, #8, 1977, (1 folders) (Box 18)
    - Journal #9, vol. 1, 1977-1978, (1 folders) (Box 18)
    - Journal, New York, #10 and adjunct journal #10 vol. 3, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Dream Journal #11A and Meditation Journal #1, vol. 11B, 1978-1979, (4 folders) (Box 18-19)
    - Dream Journals #2-3, vols. 12-13A, 1979-1981, (5 folders) (Box 19)
    - Meditation Journal #2, vol. 13B, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Dream Class Notes, vol. 13C, 1980-1981, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Dream Journal, vol. 14, 1981, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 15A, 15B, 16, 1981-1983, (7 folders) (Box 21)
    - Dream Class Notes, vol. 15C, 1982, (1 folder) (Box 21)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 16-18, 1983-1984, (8 folders) (Box 22)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 19-21, 1984-1986, (7 folders) (Box 23)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 21-24, 1986-1987, (7 folders) (Box 24)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 24-26, 1987-1988, (8 folders) (Box 25)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 27-28, 1988-1989, (8 folders) (Box 26)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 28-31, 1990-1991, (7 folders) (Box 27)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 31-32, 1991-1993, (7 folders) (Box 28)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 33-35, 1993-1995, (8 folders) (Box 29)
    - Dream Journals, vols. 36-38, 1995-1996, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    - Dream Journal, vol. 38, 1996, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Dream Journal Table of Contents, vols. 39-40, 1997-1998, (4 folders) (Box 31)
    - Dream Journal Table of Contents, vols. 40-41, 1997-1999 (Box 32)
    - [Dream Journals, unnumbered,] 1998-1999, (2 bound volumes) (Box 32)
    - Disk separation sheets (Box 32)